Address:

53, Jeyaganapathi nagar, Thiruvettakudi, Kottucherry. Karaikal. Pondicherry. 609609.

Mob : +974 31469397 +91 9487713681

E-mail: rajvigneshk@hotmail.com

VIGNESH RAJKUMAR

Objective

Looking for an organization, which provides an environment that is open and conductive to growth, offers positive work environment. I want to hone my skills across technology, also want to gain a distinct advantage for long-term career options. I have nearly 3 Years of Experience in Electrical maintenance and 1 year of CP system and Electrical construction field.

Experience

June.2018 – Dec 2019 Digital Energy Engineering Services WLL,

Doha, Qatar.

Substation Operator

July 2017 – Apr 2018 Cormit Elect Projects Pvt Ltd,

Velipalayam, Nagapattinam. TN, India.

Site Engineer

Jun.2016 – Jun. 2017 Momentum Business Associates,

Kadambadi, Nagapatinam, TN, India.

Site Engineer

Apr.2015 – Apr 2016 Tamilnadu Electricity Board (TANGEDCO/TNEB),

SE Office, Kadamparai Gen circle, Pollachi, TN, India

Apprentice Trainee

Education

B.E (Bachelor of Engineering) Anna University, Chennai. (First Class). 6.99 CGPA

D.E.E.E (Diploma in Electrical and Electronics), Valivalam desikar Polytechnic, Nagapattinam (First Class). Percentage 74.85%

Computers

MS Office, C, C++, HTML..,

Work

Experience

Profile - I

Company : Digital Energy Engineering Services WLL, Doha, Qatar. (06/2018 -12/2019)

Designation: Substation Operator - Mitsubishi Heavy industries
Project: Doha Metro /Qatar Rail Project, Doha, Qatar.

Responsibilities: -

- Operate circuit breaker switch or pushes buttons to interrupt flow of current in disturbed line preparatory to repair, and to connect alternate circuit to carry load of de energized lines.
- Controls equipment, voltage transformers and circuit breakers that regulate flow of electricity through substation of electric power system.
- Records readings of switchboard instruments to compile data concerning quantities of electric power used for substation operation and amounts distributed from station.
- Communicates with load dispatcher to report amount of electricity received into substation, and to receive switching instructions
- Operates 750V DC Switchgear for Train track power supply.
- Records temperature of transformers at specified intervals.
- Inspect equipment, such as transformers, pumps, fans, batteries, and circuit breakers to detect defects.

Profile - II

Company : Cormit Elect Projects Pvt Ltd. (07/2017 - 04/2018)

Designation : Site Engineer

Project/ Organization: MRPL, CPCL, ONGC and IOCL..,

Responsibilities: -

- Responsible for supervision of daily activities.

- Ensured that all work was completed on time, on budget and according to all applicable plans, specifications, codes and industry standards.
- Supervised crew responsible for all termination.
- Planned and scheduled hours to be worked and man hours needed.
- Maintained time sheets and checked frequently to assure work progress was being made to the standard allowances.
- Installation of Transformer Rectifier Units, cable tray installation and Earth pit.
- Installation and commissioning of CP system in Hydro carbon industries.

Profile - III

Company : **Momentum Business Associates.** (06/2016 - 06/2017)

Designation : Site Engineer

Project/ Organization: MRPL, CPCL, ONGC and IOCL..,

Responsibilities: -

- Responsible for supervision of daily activities.
- Ensured that all work was completed on time, on budget and according to all applicable plans, specifications, codes and industry standards.
- Supervised crew responsible for all termination.
- Planned and scheduled hours to be worked and man hours needed.
- Maintained time sheets and checked frequently to assure work progress was being made to the standard allowances.
- Installation of Transformer Rectifier Units, cable tray installation and Earth pit.
- Installation and commissioning of CP system in Hydro carbon industries.

Profile - IV

Company : Tamilnadu Electricity Board/ TANGEDCO. (04/2015 - 04/2016)

Designation : Apprentice Trainee

Location : 1X30 MW Hydro Electric power generating Plant Under

TANGEDCO/ TNEB

Responsibilities: -

- Connects power supply wires to machines and equipment, and connects cables and wires between machines and equipment, following manuals, schematic diagrams, and blueprints, using hand tools and test equipment.
- Replaces faulty electrical components of machine, such as relays, switches, and motors, and positions sensing devices, using hand tools. Tests electrical and equipment and parts for continuity, current, voltage, and resistance.
- Installs, repairs, or replaces AC/DC motors and drives, transformers, motors, starters, relays, and hydraulic and gas electrical controls.

- Do preventive maintenance and testing of electrical system (including 1X30 MW Hydro Electric generator and 110 KV Substation)
- Installs repairs or replaces generators and industrial storage batteries.
- Assist the Assistant Executive Engineer and Assistant Engineer office administration.

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above mentioned information are true to the best of my knowledge and I am confident that, I would be able to contribute significantly to your expectations if I am given an opportunity in your esteemed organization.

Place :	Yours truthfully
Date :	(Vignesh Rajkumar)